type Question = {
    question: string;
    answers: string[];
    correctAnswer: string;
  };


export const nervousdata = {
    questions: [
        {
            question: "Which part of the nervous system is responsible for integrating and coordinating incoming and outgoing neural signals?",
            answers: ["Peripheral nervous system",
             "Somatic nervous system",
             "Autonomic nervous system",
             "Central nervous system",
             "Sympathetic nervous system"],
            correctAnswer: "Central nervous system"
        },
        {
            question: "Nervous System consits of variety of cells. What are the two main cell types in nervous tissue?",
            answers: ["Neurons and erythrocytes",
             "Neurons and glial cells",
             "Astrocytes and oligodendrocytes",
             "Neurons and chondrocytes",
             "Fibroblasts and myocytes"],
            correctAnswer: "Neurons and glial cells"
        },
        {
            question: "There are different neuroglial cells that form myelin sheath in Central Nervous System and Peripheral Nervous System. Which cells form the myelin sheath around axons in the central nervous system?",
            answers: ["Schwann cells",
             "Astrocytes",
             "Oligodendroglia",
             "Microglia",
             "Ependymal cells"],
            correctAnswer: "Oligodendroglia"
        },
        {
            question: "There are different types of neurons in nervous system. Which type of neuron is most common in the nervous system?",
            answers: ["Bipolar neurons",
             "Unipolar neurons",
             "Multipolar neurons",
             "Sensory neurons",
             "Anaxonic neurons"],
            correctAnswer: "Multipolar neurons"
        },
        
        {
            question: "Which cells are responsible for supporting, insulating, and nourishing neurons in the central nervous system?",
            answers: ["Neurons",
             "Oligodendroglia",
             "Schwann cells",
             "Neuroglia",
             "Satellite cells"],
            correctAnswer: "Neuroglia"
        },
        {
            question: "Which type of glial cells are found in the peripheral nervous system?",
            answers: ["Astrocytes and oligodendroglia",
             "Microglia and ependymal cells",
             "Schwann and satellite cells",
             "Neurons and oligodendroglia",
             "Ependymal and astrocytes"],
            correctAnswer: "Schwann cells and satellite cells"
        },
        {
            question: "Myelin, layers of lipid, and protein substances form a myelin sheath around some axons. What is the function of myelin in the nervous system?",
            answers: ["Neurons support",
             "Brain protection",
             "Spinal cord protection",
             "Impulse conduction",
             "neuron nourishment"],
            correctAnswer: "Impulse conduction"
        },
        
        {
            question: "Nervous system is arranged into two distinct areas- gray matter and cortex. What constitutes the gray matter in both central and peripheral nervous system?",
            answers: ["Tract systems",
             "Nerve cell bodies",
             "Axons only",
             "Glial coverings",
             "Myelinated axons"],
            correctAnswer: "Nerve cell bodies"
        },
        {
            question: "There are three meningeal layers covering the brain and spinal cord. Which membranous layer of the meninges is directly attached to the brain and spinal cord?",
            answers: ["Dura mater",
             "Arachnoid mater",
             "Pia mater",
             "Epidural space",
             "Subdural space"],
            correctAnswer: "Pia mater"
        },
        
        {
            question: "Which structure anchors the spinal cord in the center of the vertebral canal?",
            answers: ["Pia mater",
             "Dura mater",
             "Arachnoid mater",
             "Denticulate ligaments",
             "Epidural space"],
            correctAnswer: "Denticulate ligaments"
        },
        {
            question: "What does the Peripheral Nervous System anatomically and operationally continuous with?",
            answers: ["Peripheral organs",
             "Central nervous system",
             "Autonomic nervous system",
             "Somatic nervous system",
             "Endocrine system"],
            correctAnswer: "Central nervous system"
        },
        {
            question: "What type of fibers in the Peripheral Nervous System convey neural impulses to the Central Nervous System from sense organs?",
            answers: ["Efferent (motor) fibers",
             "Parasympathetic fibers",
             "Sympathetic fibers",
             "Afferent (sensory) fibers",
             "Somatic fibers"],
            correctAnswer: "Afferent (sensory) fibers"
        },
        {
            question: "There are 12 pairs of Cranial nerves that arise from Brain. Through what do cranial nerves exit the cranial cavity?",
            answers: ["Intervertebral foramina",
             "Cranial sutures",
             "Foramina in the cranium",
             "Spinal canals",
             "Neural roots"],
            correctAnswer: "Foramina in the cranium"
        },
        {
            question: "How many pairs of cranial nerves arise from the brain?",
            answers: ["9",
             "10",
             "11",
             "12",
             "13"],
            correctAnswer: "11"
        },
        {
            question: "There are 31 pairs of Spinal nerves that arise from Spinal cord. How many spinal cord segments are there?",
            answers: ["29",
             "30",
             "31",
             "32",
             "33"],
            correctAnswer: "31"
        },
        {
            question: "What do the posterior and anterior nerve roots unite to form?",
            answers: ["Ganglion",
             "Synapse",
             "Spinal nerve",
             "Plexus",
             "Nucleus"],
            correctAnswer: "Spinal nerve"
        },
        // {
        //     "question": "What type of fibers do the posterior (dorsal) nerve roots consist of?",
        //     "option1": "Motor (efferent) fibers",
        //     "option2": "Autonomic fibers",
        //     "option3": "Parasympathetic fibers",
        //     "option4": "Sympathetic fibers",
        //     "option5": "Sensory (afferent) fibers",
        //     "ans": 5
        // },
        {
            question: "What is the term for unilateral area of skin supplied by a single spinal nerve?",
            answers: ["Myotome",
             "Dermatome",
             "Somite",
             "Neurotome",
             "Sclerotome"],
            correctAnswer: "Dermatome"
        },
        {
            question: "What remains separate from each other and do not merge to form major somatic nerve plexuses?",
            answers: ["Anterior rami",
            "Cranial nerves",
            "Posterior rami",
             "Spinal nerves",
             "Autonomic nerves"],
            correctAnswer: "Posterior rami"
        },
        {
            question: "What type of pattern do the posterior rami of spinal nerves innervate the skin in?",
            answers: ["Segmental",
             "Circular",
             "Lateral",
             "Linear",
             "Spiral"],
            correctAnswer: "Segmental"
        },
        {
            question: "What do anterior rami of spinal nerves participating in plexus formation contribute fibers to?",
            answers: ["Single peripheral nerves",
             "Multiple peripheral nerves",
             "Only the trunk muscles",
             "Only the limb muscles",
             "Only the skin"],
            correctAnswer: "Multiple peripheral nerves"
        },
        {
            question: "What type of distribution pattern do segmental nerves follow when forming multisegmental peripheral nerves?",
            answers: ["Dermatomal",
             "Circular",
             "Spiral",
             "Lateral",
             "Linear"],
            correctAnswer: "Dermatomal"
        },
        {
            question: "A 60-year-old patient experiences severe, intractable pain that has not responded to conventional treatments. The Neurosurgeon decides to perform a procedure at a site where the motor and sensory fibers of a spinal nerve are segregated. What is this procedure called?",
            answers: ["Neurectomy",
             "Rhizotomy",
             "Laminectomy",
             "Discectomy",
             "Foraminotomy"],
            correctAnswer: "Rhizotomy"
        },
        {
            question: "A 35-year-old male passes out after heavy drinking with his arm hanging over the edge of a chair, leading to a condition known as 'Saturday night syndrome'. What is the primary cause of this condition?",
            answers: ["Crushing nerve injury",
             "Cutting nerve injury",
             "Compression ischemia",
             "Neuritis",
             "Demyelinating disease"],
            correctAnswer: "Compression ischemia"
        },
        {
            question: "Which part of the nervous system provides sensory and motor innervation to all parts of the body except the viscera, smooth muscle, and glands?",
            answers: ["Autonomic nervous system",
             "Central nervous system",
             "Somatic nervous system",
             "Peripheral nervous system",
             "Enteric nervous system"],
            correctAnswer: "Somatic nervous system"
        },
        {
            question: "What does the somatic motor system innervate?",
            answers: ["Smooth muscle",
             "Cardiac muscle",
             "Glands",
             "Skeletal muscle",
             "Viscera"],
            correctAnswer: "Skeletal muscle"
        },
        {
            question: "Which system is described as the visceral nervous system?",
            answers: ["Autonomic nervous system",
             "Peripheral nervous system",
             "Somatic nervous system",
             "Central nervous system ",
             "Enteric nervous system"],
            correctAnswer: "Autonomic nervous system"
        },
        {
            question: "A 45-year-old male suffers a severe spinal cord injury in a car accident. Despite the proximal stumps of the injured axons beginning to regenerate, the growth is blocked by astrocyte proliferation at the injury site. What is the likely outcome of this injury?",
            answers: ["Complete motor recovery",
             "Complete sensory recovery",
             "Permanent disability",
             "Improvement with therapy",
             "Temporary paralysis"],
            correctAnswer: "Permanent disability"
        },
        {
            question: "What do somatic sensory and motor nerve fibers organized segmentally along the neural tube become parts of?",
            answers: ["All cranial nerves",
             "All spinal nerves",
             "Autonomic nerves",
             "Peripheral nerves",
             "Sympathetic chains"],
            correctAnswer: "All spinal nerves"
        },   
    ] as Question[]
};

        
                
                


                   
                        
                     

    //                         {
    //                     "question": "What percentage of sensory fibers are in nerves supplying muscles of the trunk or limbs?",
    //                     "option1": "20%",
    //                     "option2": "30%",
    //                     "option3": "40%",
    //                     "option4": "50%",
    //                     "option5": "60%",
    //                     "ans": 3
    //                 },
    //                 
                    
    //                 {
    //                     "question": "What do anterior rami of spinal nerves supply nerve fibers to?",
    //                     "option1": "The skin and muscles of the back",
    //                     "option2": "The muscles of the heart",
    //                     "option3": "The skin and hypaxial muscles of the anterior and lateral regions of the trunk and the limbs",
    //                     "option4": "The muscles of the diaphragm",
    //                     "option5": "The internal organs",
    //                     "ans": 3
    //                 },
                        
    //                     {
    //                         "question": "A patient presents with a crushing injury to a peripheral nerve. The nerve cell bodies remain intact, and the connective tissue coverings of the nerve are undamaged. What is the expected outcome without surgical intervention?",
    //                         "option1": "Complete nerve degeneration",
    //                         "option2": "Permanent loss of function",
    //                         "option3": "Nerve regeneration guided by the intact connective tissue",
    //                         "option4": "Development of a neuroma",
    //                         "option5": "Formation of scar tissue blocking regeneration",
    //                         "ans": 3
    //                     },
                        
    //                     {
    //                         "question": "A patient has a nerve injury where the axons are severed, but the nerve cell bodies remain intact. Surgical intervention is required to align the cut ends. What type of nerve injury does this describe?",
    //                         "option1": "Crushing nerve injury",
    //                         "option2": "Ischemic nerve injury",
    //                         "option3": "Cutting nerve injury",
    //                         "option4": "Compression nerve injury",
    //                         "option5": "Neuritis",
    //                         "ans": 3
    //                     }
                           
                  
//     {
//         "question": "What type of sensations does the somatic sensory system transmit?",
//         "option1": "Touch, pain, temperature, and position",
//         "option2": "Hunger, fullness, and nausea",
//         "option3": "Blood pressure and chemistry",
//         "option4": "Smooth muscle contraction",
//         "option5": "Secretory gland activity",
//         "ans": 1
//     },
    
    























//     {
//         "question": "What type of fibers stimulate smooth muscle, modified cardiac muscle, and glandular cells?",
//         "option1": "Somatic efferent fibers",
//         "option2": "Visceral afferent fibers",
//         "option3": "Somatic afferent fibers",
//         "option4": "Visceral efferent fibers",
//         "option5": "Enteric fibers",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What neurotransmitter is generally liberated by postsynaptic neurons of the sympathetic division?",
//         "option1": "Acetylcholine",
//         "option2": "Norepinephrine",
//         "option3": "Dopamine",
//         "option4": "Serotonin",
//         "option5": "Glutamate",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Where are the cell bodies of presynaptic neurons of the sympathetic division located?",
//         "option1": "Gray matter of the brainstem",
//         "option2": "Intermediolateral cell columns of the spinal cord",
//         "option3": "Autonomic ganglia",
//         "option4": "Enteric plexuses",
//         "option5": "Anterior horns of the spinal cord",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Where do the postsynaptic neurons of the sympathetic nervous system occur?",
//         "option1": "In the gray matter of the CNS",
//         "option2": "In the anterior horns of the spinal cord",
//         "option3": "In the paravertebral and prevertebral ganglia",
//         "option4": "In the intermediolateral cell columns",
//         "option5": "In the myenteric plexus",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What type of nerve fibers pass through the sympathetic trunk without synapsing?",
//         "option1": "Somatic efferent fibers",
//         "option2": "Visceral afferent fibers",
//         "option3": "Presynaptic sympathetic fibers",
//         "option4": "Postsynaptic sympathetic fibers",
//         "option5": "Cranial parasympathetic fibers",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the primary function of the sympathetic nervous system?",
//         "option1": "Regulating blood vessels",
//         "option2": "Stimulating digestive processes",
//         "option3": "Decreasing heart rate",
//         "option4": "Promoting energy conservation",
//         "option5": "Controlling voluntary muscle movement",
//         "ans": 1
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which nerves convey visceral efferent and afferent fibers to and from the viscera of the body cavities?",
//         "option1": "Cardiopulmonary nerves",
//         "option2": "Splanchnic nerves",
//         "option3": "Pelvic nerves",
//         "option4": "Cephalic arterial rami",
//         "option5": "Periarterial plexuses",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Where are the presynaptic parasympathetic nerve cell bodies located?",
//         "option1": "Gray matter of the brainstem and sacral segments of the spinal cord",
//         "option2": "Gray matter of the thoracic segments of the spinal cord",
//         "option3": "Intermediolateral cell columns",
//         "option4": "Paravertebral ganglia",
//         "option5": "Prevertebral ganglia",
//         "ans": 1
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which nerve provides parasympathetic innervation to most of the gastrointestinal tract?",
//         "option1": "Pelvic splanchnic nerves",
//         "option2": "Glossopharyngeal nerve",
//         "option3": "Facial nerve",
//         "option4": "Vagus nerve",
//         "option5": "Hypoglossal nerve",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Where do the presynaptic parasympathetic fibers synapse with postsynaptic cell bodies?",
//         "option1": "In the gray matter of the brainstem",
//         "option2": "In the autonomic ganglia",
//         "option3": "In the wall of the target organ",
//         "option4": "In the spinal cord",
//         "option5": "In the sympathetic trunk",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which system is described as the 'second brain' due to its complexity and integrative function?",
//         "option1": "Sympathetic nervous system",
//         "option2": "Parasympathetic nervous system",
//         "option3": "Central nervous system",
//         "option4": "Enteric nervous system",
//         "option5": "Peripheral nervous system",
//         "ans": 4
//     }
// ]




